<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning | AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/tag/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/tag/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Technical University of Munich 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aim-lab.io/images/icon_hu90763c276d9f69c3ad22e431a6bb6670_11797_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/tag/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Interpreting age prediction in whole body MR images</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/age_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/age_prediction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Age prediction has been investigated intensively for brain imaging (brain age estimation) [1]. Here, it has been applied for early prediction of neurodegenerative diseases and the assessment of accelerated aging. However, there is very little research on abdominal age prediction which estimates the age of a person based on abdominal organs [2]. The goal of this project is to extend a previously implemented age prediction algorithm, which uses full body MR images as an input and apply interpretability methods like GradCAM on different slices as areas of the image, to investigate which parts of the body are predictive of a person’s age. This can lead to medical insights about accelerated aging of different areas of the body, as well as which parts of the body are most relevant to estimate age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work will be using a dataset of about 40,000 whole body MR images from the UK Biobank [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master&amp;rsquo;s student in Computer Science or a closely related programme. You should bring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in medical image processing;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior knowledge in machine learning and a commonly used DL framework (PyTorch, Tensorflow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a background in computer vision (e.g. from one of the CV courses)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An exciting project on real world medical data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a large dataset with annotations from medical experts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;an interdisciplinary team of high qualified experts in image processing, computer vision, deep learning, and medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Sajedi, Hedieh, and Nastaran Pardakhti. &amp;ldquo;Age prediction based on brain MRI image: a survey.&amp;rdquo; Journal of medical systems 43.8 (2019): 1-30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Le Goallec, A., Diai, S., Collin, S. et al. Using deep learning to predict abdominal age from liver and pancreas magnetic resonance images. Nat Commun 13, 1979 (2022). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-29525-9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-29525-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ukbiobank.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.ukbiobank.ac.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Course: Applied Deep Learning in Medicine</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this course students are given the chance to apply their abilities and knowledge in deep learning to real-world medical data. Students will be assigned a medical dataset and in close consultation with medical doctors create a project plan. Deep Learning methods will be applied to solve tasks to achieve the goal that is agreed upon. Datasets will be explored and analysed in several directions and different approaches will be evaluated and compared.
In short this course offers students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply Deep Learning in the real world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on medical data and potentially help diagnose and analyse health related problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision by PhD students with specialization in AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaboration with medical experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on the intersection between medicine and computer science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed at least one or several machine learning or deep learning courses (e.g. Intro to Deep Learning, Advanced Deep Learning, Machine Learning etc) with good grades. Knowledge about augmentation, optimizer, common model architectures, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good coding skills in python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding experience in one or more deep learning frameworks (Tensorflow, PyTorch, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for the application in the medical field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to tackle applied deep learning projects in a structured manner with a good overview of possibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gained insight into the problems of medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final outcome as a useful insight or tool for medical professionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible outcome will be published in a peer-reviewed venue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will work in teams of three&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group will be assigned one medical dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Bi)weekly meetings with progress reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-meeting&#34;&gt;Preliminary meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A preliminary meeting will take place on 20th of July, 2022 at 11:00 on zoom with the following details: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting ID: 690 7588 3519 &lt;br&gt;
Passcode: 850155&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeetingWS22.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides - WS 2022/23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeeting.pdf&#34;&gt;(Outdated) Slides - SoSe 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
