<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Imaging | AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/tag/medical-imaging/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/tag/medical-imaging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Medical Imaging</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Technical University of Munich 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aim-lab.io/images/icon_hu90763c276d9f69c3ad22e431a6bb6670_11797_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/tag/medical-imaging/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Course: Applied Deep Learning in Medicine</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/alexziller/practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/alexziller/practical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this course students are given the chance to apply their abilities and knowledge in deep learning to real-world medical data. Students will be assigned a medical dataset and in close consultation with medical doctors create a project plan. Deep Learning methods will be applied to solve tasks to achieve the goal that is agreed upon. Datasets will be explored and analysed in several directions and different approaches will be evaluated and compared.
In short this course offers students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply Deep Learning in the real world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on medical data and potentially help diagnose and analyse health related problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision by PhD students with specialization in AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaboration with medical experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on the intersection between medicine and computer science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed at least one or several machine learning or deep learning courses (e.g. Intro to Deep Learning, Advanced Deep Learning, Machine Learning etc) with good grades. Knowledge about augmentation, optimizer, common model architectures, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good coding skills in python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding experience in one or more deep learning frameworks (Tensorflow, PyTorch, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for the application in the medical field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to tackle applied deep learning projects in a structured manner with a good overview of possibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gained insight into the problems of medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final outcome as a useful insight or tool for medical professionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible outcome will be published in a peer-reviewed venue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will work in teams of three&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group will be assigned one medical dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Bi)weekly meetings with progress reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-meeting&#34;&gt;Preliminary meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A preliminary meeting will take place on 12th of July, 2023 at 10:00 on zoom with the following details:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519&#34;&gt;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting ID: 690 7588 3519&lt;br&gt;
Passcode: 850155&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeetingWiSe2324.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides - WS 2023/24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeetingSoSe23.pdf&#34;&gt;(Outdated) Slides - SoSe 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeetingWS22.pdf&#34;&gt;(Outdated) Slides - WS 2022/23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeeting.pdf&#34;&gt;(Outdated) Slides - SoSe 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master-Seminar: Unsupervised Anomaly Detection in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/felixmeissen/seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/felixmeissen/seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cover image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anomaly detection aims to identify patterns that do not conform to the expected normal distribution.
Despite its importance for clinical applications, the detection of outliers is still a very challenging task due to the
rarity, unknownness, diversity and heterogeneity of abnormalities.
Basic problem formulations to recent advances in the field will be discussed.
This includes, but is not limited to: reconstruction-based
auto-encoders (AE) adversarial methods, diffusion models, and others.
In short this course offers students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to critically read and understand scientific papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get hands-on practice in implementing anomaly detection methods on medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice the presentation and discussion of experimental results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a multi-facetted view in multiple guest lecturers by reknown researchers in the field of anomaly detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding of Deep Learning and Neural Networks, demonstrated through the completion of at least one learning or deep learning course (e.g. Intro to Deep Learning, Advanced Deep Learning, Machine Learning, or equivalent).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good coding skills in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding experience in PyTorch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in medical imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will select a relevant paper and present it critically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They will then implement the method in the paper given our framework and data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimental results will be presented to the lecturers and fellow students in a poster session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- ## Preliminary meeting
A preliminary meeting will take place on 31st of January, 2023 at 11:30 on zoom with the following details: https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519 

Meeting ID: 690 7588 3519 \
Passcode: 850155  --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
