<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vasiliki Sideri-Lampretsa | AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/vasiliki-sideri-lampretsa/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/author/vasiliki-sideri-lampretsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Vasiliki Sideri-Lampretsa</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Technical University of Munich 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aim-lab.io/images/icon_hu90763c276d9f69c3ad22e431a6bb6670_11797_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Vasiliki Sideri-Lampretsa</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/vasiliki-sideri-lampretsa/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Combining longitudinal volumetric imaging and tabular data for depression prediction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/depression_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/depression_prediction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The objective of this project is to combine volumetric imaging and non-imaging longitudinal data to accurately analyze individual patients and provide automated decisions regarding diagnosis and disease prognosis. Physicians consider various medical biomarkers and meta-data to reach a clinical decision. Thus, creating computer-assisted diagnostic systems that operate in a similar manner could be highly beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to align imaging and other medical information, such as medical history, blood values, sleep habits, genetic information, and more, in the feature space using a contrastive loss. The approach will integrate multiple modalities of each patient from various time points in the same model in an end-to-end fashion. The method can be fully supervised or be used in a self-supervision scheme, in which our model can learn the aligned embedding space of imaging and non-imaging data using a proxy task from the data itself. Afterward, the learned embeddings can be finetuned for downstream tasks, such as depression prediction [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project will be completed under the supervision of Dr. Magdalini Paschali (Stanford University) and Vasiliki Sideri-Lampretsa (TUM). Computational resources and datasets [1] will be provided.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aadvanced knowledge in machine learning and computer vision – ability to understand and reproduce state-of-the-art publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good programming skills in Python (numpy, pandas, seaborn, scikit-learn) and PyTorch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent communication skills and ability to work remotely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting, international research project with real world medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freedom to come up with and propose your own ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPU resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An interdisciplinary team of high qualified experts in deep learning, statistics, medical imaging, and neuroscience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunity to participate in lab meetings as well as a workspace in TranslaTUM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Paschali, M., Kiss, O., Zhao, Q., Adeli, E., Podhajsky, S., Müller-Oehring, E.M., Gotlib, I.H., Pohl, K.M. and Baker, F.C., 2022. Detecting negative valence symptoms in adolescents based on longitudinal self-reports and behavioral assessments. Journal of Affective Disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Brown, S.A., Brumback, T.Y., Tomlinson, K., Cummins, K., Thompson, W.K., Nagel, B.J., De Bellis, M.D., Hooper, S.R., Clark, D.B., Chung, T. and Hasler, B.P., 2015. The National Consortium on Alcohol and NeuroDevelopment in Adolescence (NCANDA): a multisite study of adolescent development and substance use. Journal of studies on alcohol and drugs, 76(6), pp.895-908.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
