<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AI in Medicine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Technical University of Munich {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 21:26:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The developing Human Connectome Project (dHCP) automated resting-state functional processing framework for newborn infants</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/publication/neuroimage2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 21:26:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/publication/neuroimage2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Machine Learning in Fetal MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/fetal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/fetal/</guid>
      <description>Fetal Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) has become increasingly important to assess the development of the fetal brain. However, the acquisition is challenging due to the uncontrollable fetal motion. This requires both improved MR acquisition and reconstruction procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Motion-Compensated MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/motionmri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/motionmri/</guid>
      <description>Long acquisition times in Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) bear the risk of patient motion, which substantially degrades the image quality. Further sources of image degradation are physiological motion, such as periodic respiratory and cardiac motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Physics-Driven Self-Supervised Learning in MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/physicsmri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/physicsmri/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning has evolved tremendously to accelerate the inherently low acquisition process of Magnetic Resonance (MR) images. However, it is challenging to obtain ground truth data for learning MRI reconstruction. The objective of this MSc thesis is to explore self-supervised learning for MRI reconstruction, where only the measurement (k-space) data and knowledge about the acquisition physics are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Distributionally robust neural networks in medical imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/robust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/robust/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning has revolutionized the field of medical imaging. However, the performance of a model drops when the distribution of the test data is different from the distribution of the training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Out-of-distribution detection using contrastive training for medical imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/oodd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/oodd/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning has revolutionized the field of medical imaging. However, the performance of a model drops when the distribution of the test data is different from the distribution of the training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Applied Federated Deep Learning in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/applied_fedl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/applied_fedl/</guid>
      <description>Distributed deep learning systems can help ascertain data governance and sovereignty while allowing the training of algorithms on larger an more diverse datasets. This is particularly beneficial in the medical domain, in which the collection and curation of large datasets is especially difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Privacy-preserving Deep Learning in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/ppml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/ppml/</guid>
      <description>Privacy-preserving artificial intelligence techniques such as differential privacy, encryption and multi-party computation can reconcile the needs for data utilisation and data protection in the medical domain, as mandated by legal and ethical requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model-Based and Data-Driven Strategies in Medical Image Computing</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/publication/proc-ieee-2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 12:39:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/publication/proc-ieee-2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, privacy-preserving and federated machine learning in medical imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/www.nature.com/articles/s42256-020-0186-1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 06:59:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/www.nature.com/articles/s42256-020-0186-1</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Anschrift Technische Universität München Arcisstraße 21 80333 München Umsatzsteueridentifikationsnummer: DE811193231 Zuständige Aufsichtsbehörde Bayerisches Staatsministerium für Wissenschaft und Kunst Inhaltlich verantwortlich Prof. Dr. Daniel Rückert
Technische Universität München / Klinikum Rechts der Isar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A population-based phenome-wide association study of cardiac and aortic structure and function</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/publication/nat-med-2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:33:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/publication/nat-med-2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic and functional insights into the fractal structure of the heart</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/publication/nat-2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:33:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/publication/nat-2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
