<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>AI in Medicine</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Technical University of Munich 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aim-lab.io/images/icon_hu90763c276d9f69c3ad22e431a6bb6670_11797_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>AI in Medicine</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Spatiotemporal Contrastive Learning of Progressive Diseases</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/temporal_contrastive_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/temporal_contrastive_learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrastive learning is currently the most effective way to learn representations in a self-supervised manner. Its strength lies in training networks to solve a context-matching task using multiple views of an image. If the views are smartly chosen through proper augmentations, the model learns informative representations of data without any human supervision. These representations can then be used on targeted downstream tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrastive learning has been explored extensively in the natural image domain but there still remain many unanswered questions and untapped potential in the medical domain. The unique characteristics of medical data offers many avenues to explore to try and determine how best to adapt contrastive learning to medical imaging. In this project, we are interested in the temporal dimension in two very large medical datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our main application will be for learning representations of the evolution of progressive diseases. Despite being the leading cause of blindness in the elderly, little is understood about how Age-related macular degeneration (AMD) develops over time. This evolution is documented in our dataset of 181k retinal images of 7.5k subjects imaged over eight years. Using the self-supervised  methodology you develop, you will also learn representations that encode multiple years of disease progression, ultimately improving diagnosis and prognosis of AMD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A secondary application, to test the generalisability of the method, is cardiac MR imaging. Here we will train models to learn the dynamics of the heart as it cycles at least one heart beat, which is important for predicting cardiac disease such as infarction. The full cycle cardiac MR data from the UKBB contains over 45k subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-accomplish-this-work-successfully-we-expect-you-to-have&#34;&gt;To accomplish this work successfully, we expect you to have:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong coding skills and familiarity with Pytorch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge of contrastive learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A strong spirit of independent work and desire to solve interesting research questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of experts in image processing, deep learning, biomedical engineering and medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support in bringing your finished project to publication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.05709.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A Simple Framework for Contrastive Learning of Visual Representations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2104.14558.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A Large-Scale Study on Unsupervised Spatiotemporal Representation Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href=&#34;https://faculty.ucmerced.edu/mhyang/papers/cvpr2021_cvrl.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Spatiotemporal Contrastive Video Representation Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to apply:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:robert.holland15@imperial.ac.uk&#34;&gt;robert.holland15@imperial.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:paul.hager@tum.de&#34;&gt;paul.hager@tum.de&lt;/a&gt; with your CV and transcript. We promise to get back to you within a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Diffusion model for Graph Generation</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/masther_thesis_relationformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/masther_thesis_relationformer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Master thesis we aim to address the graph extraction problem using a new powerful class of neural networks - Diffusion [2]. A comprehensive representation of an image requires understanding objects and their mutual relationship, especially in image-to-graph generation, e.g., road network extraction, blood-vessel network extraction, or scene graph generation. 
Traditionally, image-to-graph generation is addressed with a two-stage approach consisting of object detection followed by a separate relation prediction, which prevents simultaneous object-relation interaction. In our recent ECCV paper, we proposed a unified one-stage transformer-based framework, namely &lt;em&gt;Relationformer&lt;/em&gt; that jointly predicts objects and their relations [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our applications will be large scale biological applications for example the whole brain vasculature [3] or neurons as well as satellite imagery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./relationformer.png&#34; alt=&#34;image transformer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. Your goal is to extend the existing Pytorch codebase and apply it to novel datasets. You will be working together with Suprosanna and Johannes, two PostDocs scientist at TU Munich and Imperial College London under the supervision of Prof. Daniel Rückert. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact machine learning conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in C++, Python or C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong interest in teamwork and interdisciplinary research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of highly qualified experts in machine learning, computer vision and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to apply:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:suprosanna.shit@tum.de&#34;&gt;suprosanna.shit@tum.de&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:j.paetzold@ic.ac.uk&#34;&gt;j.paetzold@ic.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;, with a short CV and your grade report. We promise to get back to you within days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./vessels.png&#34; alt=&#34;image vessel&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Shit, Suprosanna, et al. &amp;ldquo;Relationformer: A Unified Framework for Image-to-Graph Generation.&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.10202&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.10202&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Chen et al. &amp;ldquo;DiffusionDet: Diffusion Model for Object Detection.&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2211.09788.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2211.09788.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Paetzold, Johannes C., et al. &amp;ldquo;Whole Brain Vessel Graphs: A Dataset and Benchmark for Graph Learning and Neuroscience.&amp;rdquo; Thirty-fifth Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems Datasets and Benchmarks Track (Round 2). 2021.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Automatic recognition of billing codes based on dental documentation using Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/boryschibisov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/boryschibisov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are an international team of experts in the field of NLP and AI looking for a highly motivated Master&amp;rsquo;s student to join us for a master thesis project. Our main focus is the development of Doctos, an app that generates dental documentation through speech-to-text and converts the documentation into relevant billing codes using Named Entity Recognition. The documentation and the generated billing codes are automatically imported into the relevant PVS.
The objective of this thesis is to compare different methods for automatic recognition of billing codes from dental documentation. In particular, the focus will be on Named Entity Recognition techniques and their implementation in Doctos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Science, Mathematics or similar background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong background in NLP and machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in medical documentation and healthcare technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proficient in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with Huggingface and NLP frameworks such as PyTorch, Tensorflow, or Keras (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluent in German&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A close, personal supervision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A unique opportunity to work in an interdisciplinary team and contribute to the development of Doctos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to cutting-edge technologies and techniques in NLP and AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A unique opportunity to contribute to the development of a game-changing app in the healthcare industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in this opportunity, please get in touch with us to discuss further details and to find an individual topic! This project is in collaboration with Doctos and under supervision of Bory Chibisov (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bc@doctos.de&#34;&gt;bc@doctos.de&lt;/a&gt;) and Prof. Pförringer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: transfer learning for segmentation of tubular structures in thoracic CT images</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/thoracic_ct_processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/thoracic_ct_processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computed tomography (CT) scans are commonly used in clinic practice to diagnose and monitor diseases of the lung, heart and upper abdomen [1]. Deep learning has seen wide-spread application for the segmentation of organs in CT images [2,3]. However, its use for segmentation of complex, tubular structures, such as the bronchial proximal airways or cardiac vasculature, has been inhibited by a lack of high-quality ground truth labels [4]. In this research project, the prospective student will investigate the use of unsupervised learning and transfer learning to segment complex structures in chest CT images without having to rely on large amounts of ground truth annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for deep learning and biomedical imaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced knowledge of machine learning and computer vision. Ideally, prior work experience using deep learning for image processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python as well as PyTorch or Tensorflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full time commitment towards the completion of your Master&amp;rsquo;s project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of experts in image processing, deep learning, biomedical engineering and medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to apply:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:martin.menten@tum.de&#34;&gt;martin.menten@tum.de&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:veronika.zimmer@tum.de&#34;&gt;veronika.zimmer@tum.de&lt;/a&gt; with your CV and transcript. We aim to get back to you within a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Grainger, Ronald G., and David J. Allison, eds. Grainger &amp;amp; Allison&amp;rsquo;s diagnostic radiology: a textbook of medical imaging. Vol. 1. Churchill Livingstone, 1997.&lt;br&gt;
[2] Dong, Xue, et al. &amp;ldquo;Automatic multiorgan segmentation in thorax CT images using U‐net‐GAN.&amp;rdquo; Medical physics 46.5 (2019): 2157-2168.&lt;br&gt;
[3] Wasserthal, Jakob, et al. &amp;ldquo;TotalSegmentator: robust segmentation of 104 anatomical structures in CT images.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:2208.05868 (2022).&lt;br&gt;
[4] Willemink, Martin J., et al. &amp;ldquo;Preparing medical imaging data for machine learning.&amp;rdquo; Radiology 295.1 (2020): 4-15.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Brain age predicition using resting-state electroencephography (EEG)</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/eeg_age_predicition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/eeg_age_predicition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The electroencephalogram (EEG) is a tool that allows non-invasive monitoring of the brain activity. Thin electrodes placed on the scalp detect tiny electrical charges that result from the activity of brain cells. Given the simple and low-cost setup, in clinical medicine the EEG is used by neurologists to evaluate brain disorders (e.g. epilepsy), to diagnose diseases (e.g. Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease, narcolepsy), or simply to monitor blood flow in the brain. [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the context of this thesis, a dataset containing the EEGs of chronic pain patients (chronic backpain, chronic widespread pain, joint pain, and neuropathic pain) and an age-matching healthy control group is provided by the University Hospital rechts der Isar. Previous work on EEG data of chronic pain patients has shown an increased brain connectivity at specific frequencies in frontal brain areas when compared to the healthy control group. [2] Furthermore, longitudinal studies indicate a global brain network change in chronic pain patients. [3] In this thesis we will investigate how brain age is affected by chronic diseases. Self-supervised learning and transfer learning techniques will be leveraged to understand the high-level context of an EEG. The learned EEG representation is then used to predict the brain age. We will analyse the differences in brain age between chronic pain patients and the healthy control group.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background in computer science, engineering, mathematics, or similar studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic knowledge of signal processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced knowledge of machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python and a common DL framework (PyTorch, Tensorflow, JAX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent working style with strong interest in teamwork and methodic research
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to perform cutting edge research in the field of neuroscience and deep learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to high-end computer hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closely working and collabroting in an inter-disciplinary team of experts in signal processing, deep learning, neuroscience and medicine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This project is targeting publication at leading neuroscience journals
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to apply:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send us a short e-mail with your CV and grade report to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:oezguen.turgut@tum.de&#34;&gt;oezguen.turgut@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Johns Hopkins Medicine. &amp;ldquo;Electroencephalogram (EEG)&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/treatment-tests-and-therapies/electroencephalogram-eeg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/treatment-tests-and-therapies/electroencephalogram-eeg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/br&gt;
[2] Dinh et al. &amp;ldquo;Brain dysfunction in chronic pain patients assessed by resting-state electroencephalography.&amp;rdquo; Pain 160.12 (2019): 2751.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7195856/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7195856/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/br&gt;
[3] Heitmann et al. &amp;ldquo;Longitudinal resting-state electroencephalography in patients with chronic pain undergoing interdisciplinary multimodal pain therapy.&amp;rdquo; Pain 163.9 (2022): e997-e1005.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35050961/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35050961/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Course: Applied Deep Learning in Medicine</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this course students are given the chance to apply their abilities and knowledge in deep learning to real-world medical data. Students will be assigned a medical dataset and in close consultation with medical doctors create a project plan. Deep Learning methods will be applied to solve tasks to achieve the goal that is agreed upon. Datasets will be explored and analysed in several directions and different approaches will be evaluated and compared.
In short this course offers students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply Deep Learning in the real world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on medical data and potentially help diagnose and analyse health related problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision by PhD students with specialization in AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaboration with medical experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on the intersection between medicine and computer science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed at least one or several machine learning or deep learning courses (e.g. Intro to Deep Learning, Advanced Deep Learning, Machine Learning etc) with good grades. Knowledge about augmentation, optimizer, common model architectures, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good coding skills in python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding experience in one or more deep learning frameworks (Tensorflow, PyTorch, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for the application in the medical field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to tackle applied deep learning projects in a structured manner with a good overview of possibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gained insight into the problems of medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final outcome as a useful insight or tool for medical professionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible outcome will be published in a peer-reviewed venue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will work in teams of three&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group will be assigned one medical dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Bi)weekly meetings with progress reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-meeting&#34;&gt;Preliminary meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A preliminary meeting will take place on 31st of January, 2023 at 11:30 on zoom with the following details: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting ID: 690 7588 3519 &lt;br&gt;
Passcode: 850155&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeetingSoSe23.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides - SoSe 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeetingWS22.pdf&#34;&gt;(Outdated) Slides - WS 2022/23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeeting.pdf&#34;&gt;(Outdated) Slides - SoSe 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Fairness in Unsupervised Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/anomaly_detection_fairness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/anomaly_detection_fairness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unsupervised anomaly detection methods use unlabeled data from one distribution for training and can then differentiate between samples that come from that distribution and samples from other distributions.
In medical applications, anomalies often correspond to diseases and can be detected with such methods. This is a way to make use of the large amounts of clinically unremarkable data available.
While it is known that supervised machine learning models show worse performance for minority groups that are usually underrepresented in the data, this problem has so far not been studied for unsupervised methods despite the large implications a potentially unfair clinical application could have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Masters Thesis will investigate (un)fairness of anomaly detection models used for medical disease detection under different definitions of fairness and will try to offer mitigation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your Qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most important: solid coding skills and familiarity with PyTorch and Numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong background in machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivated master student in Informatics, Mathematics, Physics or a closely related field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to thoroughly answer a research question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong research mindset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:felix.meissen@tum.de&#34;&gt;felix.meissen@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;, with a short CV and your grade report. We promise to get back to you within days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Scaling Laws of Equivariant Convolutions</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/scaling_laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/scaling_laws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Equivariant convolutions are a novel approach that incorporate additional geometric properties of the input domain during the convolution process (i.e. symmetry properties such as rotations and reflections) [1]. This additional inductive bias allows the model to learn more robust and general features from less data, rendering them highly promising for application in the medical domain. So far, however, nobody has investigated how their beneficial characteristics impact the design and scaling of deep learning model architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have developed a framework for initial investigation of equivariant convolutions and now want to evaluate how their performance can be further increased with larger model sizes and under different training regimes. This work plans to build onto previous highly impactful research on model design, such as the establishment of the EfficientNet architecture and the Chinchilla language model, to create a sound basis for the further consolidation of equivariant convolutions in the broader research landscape [2, 3]. The focus will be to thoroughly analyze and expand a framework for equivariant models already developed at our lab. This includes getting familiar with model architectures in general, the properties of equivariant convolutions and the intersection of the two. Our goal is to develop a methodological framework for equivariant model architectures that can be easily adapted to the properties of the used dataset and are able to beat state-of-the-art non-equivariant alternatives in standard and privacy-preserving deep learning settings [4].
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. You will establish a comprehensive pipeline in PyTorch or JAX to evaluate the properties of equivariant models on different benchmark datasets. You will be working at the institute for AI in Medicine, at the Privacy-Preserving and Trustworthy Machine Learning Group. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact deep learning conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in deep learning and learning theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python and a common DL framework (PyTorch, Tensorflow, JAX).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent working style with strong interest in teamwork and methodic research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting state-of-the-art research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to the necessary computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of highly qualified experts in image processing, computer vision and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Cohen and Welling (2016). Group Equivariant Convolutions. ICML 2016. &lt;/br&gt;
[2] Tan and Le (2019). EfficientNet: Rethinking Model Scaling for Convolutional Neural Networks. ICML 2019. &lt;/br&gt;
[3] Hoffmann et al. (2022). Training Compute-Optimal Large Language Models. ArXiv, abs/2203.15556. &lt;/br&gt;
[4] Abadi et al. (2016). Deep Learning with Differential Privacy. ACM SIGSAC 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis/Guided Research/IDP: Efficient Training under Differential Privacy</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/efficient_training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/efficient_training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Differential privacy (DP) is the gold standard of privacy-preserving deep learning and has seen increasing interest in the last few years, especially in the medical domain, where the protection of sensitive data is of highest interest [1]. Privacy in deep learning, however, still comes at a high privacy-utility trade-off that restricts the practical usability of models trained under DP. We, as researchers, try to solve this issue by looking into learning theory and by developing novel approaches that allow DP networks to challenge non-private approaches in clinical application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two properties that affect all differentially private networks are model size and the chosen privacy parameters during training. In this work, we plan to analyze these two areas and introduce changes to the training regime, that improve not only the performance of the models but also reduce their computational overhead. The goal is to 1) build on top of research done on learning sparse neural networks and correspondingly adapt the model parameters during training [2]. And 2), we look at the amount of total noise added during training with DP and evaluate, how to adapt the corresponding privacy parameters without any knowledge about the model or dataset [3]. If successful, this research can be applied to any differential private model in a plug-and-play fashion during training to further reduce the privacy-utility trade-off.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. You will establish a comprehensive pipeline in PyTorch or JAX to evaluate the model sparsity and changing privacy-parameters on different benchmark datasets for models trained under DP. You will be working at the institute for AI in Medicine, at the Privacy-Preserving and Trustworthy Machine Learning Group. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact deep learning conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in deep learning and learning theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python and a common DL framework (PyTorch, Tensorflow, JAX).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent working style with strong interest in teamwork and methodic research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting state-of-the-art research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to the necessary computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of highly qualified experts in image processing, computer vision and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Abadi et al. (2016). Deep Learning with Differential Privacy. ACM SIGSAC 2016. &lt;/br&gt;
[2] Louizos et al. (2018). Learning sparse neural networks through L0 regularization. ICLR 2018. &lt;/br&gt;
[3] Sander et al. (2022). TAN without a burn: Scaling Laws of DP-SGD. ArXiv, abs/2210.03403.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: An attention-based image denoising network leveraging information of both spatial and frequency domain</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/denosing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/denosing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image denoising task, in which a clean image is recovered from a noise observation, is a classical inverse problem and still active topic in low-level vision since it is an indispensable step in many practical applications. In past decades, a large variety of image denoising methods employing neural networks were proposed to solve this inverse problem. These methods are major in the spatial domain which denoise the image straightforwardly by extracting the spatial information using the sliding CNN window. On the other hand, image denoising from the frequency domain also has a long history in which the low-pass filter techniques are applied and the noise (major in high-frequency space) can be filtered out. The denoising optimization in the frequency domain is frequently utilized in medical image reconstruction. Recently a great number of frequency networks with CNNs are used in this field to improve the reconstruction quality. However, this approach is rarely studied in the nature denoising field with RGB images. More recently, the advent of Transformers evolutes the computer vision field. Its inherent attributes like larger receptive field and lower inductive bias facilitate the image denoising tasks.
In this work, we attempt to introduce a hybrid image denoising network that optimizes the noise image from both spatial and frequency domain. A comparison with SOTA methods on public datasets like urban100 or SIDD will be conducted in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-accomplish-this-work-successfully-we-expect-you-have&#34;&gt;To accomplish this work successfully, we expect you have:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most important: solid coding skills and familiarity with Pytorch and Numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of the state-of-the-art image denoising methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of the state-of-the-art CNN and Transformer approaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of Fourier transformation and frequency optimization methods/network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent work spirit of finding, research reading and solving a research problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of experts in image processing, deep learning, biomedical engineering and medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to apply:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jiazhen.pan@tum.de&#34;&gt;jiazhen.pan@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;, with a short CV and your grade report. We promise to get back to you within days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Motion-Compensated MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/motionmri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/motionmri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long acquisition times in Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) bear the risk of patient motion, which substantially degrades the image quality. Further sources of image degradation are physiological motion, such as periodic respiratory and cardiac motion. Accelerated acquisitions can compensate for the motion. The motion information can also be derived from the acquired MRI data retrospectively and used as a correction step in image reconstruction. The objective of this thesis is to include the motion model directly in MRI reconstruction using both knowledge of the acquisition physics and machine learning. Motion-Compensated MRI reconstruction offers a wide range of opportunities for projects, where we can set the emphasis based on your interests. Please get in touch with us to find an individual topic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Science, Biomedical Engineering or similar background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong background in machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in medical imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proficient  in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with ML frameworks, e.g., PyTorch / Tensorflow / Keras (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer&#34;&gt;We offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a close, personal supervision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to work in an interdisciplinary team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to collaborate with international experts in machine learning and MR image reconstruction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Combining longitudinal volumetric imaging and tabular data for depression prediction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/depression_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/depression_prediction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The objective of this project is to combine volumetric imaging and non-imaging longitudinal data to accurately analyze individual patients and provide automated decisions regarding diagnosis and disease prognosis. Physicians consider various medical biomarkers and meta-data to reach a clinical decision. Thus, creating computer-assisted diagnostic systems that operate in a similar manner could be highly beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to align imaging and other medical information, such as medical history, blood values, sleep habits, genetic information, and more, in the feature space using a contrastive loss. The approach will integrate multiple modalities of each patient from various time points in the same model in an end-to-end fashion. The method can be fully supervised or be used in a self-supervision scheme, in which our model can learn the aligned embedding space of imaging and non-imaging data using a proxy task from the data itself. Afterward, the learned embeddings can be finetuned for downstream tasks, such as depression prediction [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project will be completed under the supervision of Dr. Magdalini Paschali (Stanford University) and Vasiliki Sideri-Lampretsa (TUM). Computational resources and datasets [1] will be provided.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aadvanced knowledge in machine learning and computer vision – ability to understand and reproduce state-of-the-art publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good programming skills in Python (numpy, pandas, seaborn, scikit-learn) and PyTorch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent communication skills and ability to work remotely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting, international research project with real world medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freedom to come up with and propose your own ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPU resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An interdisciplinary team of high qualified experts in deep learning, statistics, medical imaging, and neuroscience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunity to participate in lab meetings as well as a workspace in TranslaTUM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Paschali, M., Kiss, O., Zhao, Q., Adeli, E., Podhajsky, S., Müller-Oehring, E.M., Gotlib, I.H., Pohl, K.M. and Baker, F.C., 2022. Detecting negative valence symptoms in adolescents based on longitudinal self-reports and behavioral assessments. Journal of Affective Disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Brown, S.A., Brumback, T.Y., Tomlinson, K., Cummins, K., Thompson, W.K., Nagel, B.J., De Bellis, M.D., Hooper, S.R., Clark, D.B., Chung, T. and Hasler, B.P., 2015. The National Consortium on Alcohol and NeuroDevelopment in Adolescence (NCANDA): a multisite study of adolescent development and substance use. Journal of studies on alcohol and drugs, 76(6), pp.895-908.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Federated, privacy preserving deep learning for fetal MRI brain segmentation</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/maik/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/maik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In medical domain data protection and privacy preservation is highly relevant. Therefore, clinical data of patients is usually securely stored on clinic servers without access from outside.
Publication of clinical data is difficult and cumbersome as strict privacy and data protection laws must be obeyed.
These involve anonymization of patient data, drafting of data sharing agreements, and the approval of the corresponding ethics commission.
This complex publication process is one of the key reasons for data shortage in medical domain and is often preventing machine learning approaches to reach their full potential.
Federated learning [1] paired with differential privacy [2,3] can circumvent the problem of data publication.
Rather than gathering the data from clinical sites to centrally train a machine learning model, the model is distributed to the different sites, locally trained on the (partial) data, and finally, globally aggregated [2].
Thus, patient data is never seen by third parties.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to construct a proof of concept for a federated learning approach in the domain of fetal MRI segmentation. An existing baseline segmentation model must be modified and embedded in a federated learning environment. The model must then be trained on fetal MRI scans located on several international clinic servers. Furthermore, sufficient privacy standards (e.g. differential privacy [2]) must be discussed and ensured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;advanced knowledge in machine learning and computer vision (experience in federated learning or differential privacy is helpful but not mandatory)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;good programming skills in Python and a deep learning framework (previous work is based on
PyTorch).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;good communication skills. The project will require you to cooperate with different clinics of various countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;insight to an international research project with real world medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;freedom to come up with-, and to pursue your own ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hardware (sufficient GPU resources)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an interdisciplinary team of high qualified experts in image processing, deep
learning, federated learning, and differential privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Jakub Konečný et al. “Federated learning: Strategies for improving communication efficiency”.
In: arXiv preprint arXiv:1610.05492 (2016).&lt;br/&gt;
[2] Georgios Kaissis et al. “End-to-end privacy preserving deep learning on multi-institutional medical
imaging”. In: Nature Machine Intelligence 3.6 (2021), pp. 473–484.&lt;br/&gt;
[3] Alexander Ziller et al. “Differentially private federated deep learning for multi-site medical image
segmentation”. In: arXiv preprint arXiv:2107.02586 (2021).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Non-invasive and accurate prediction of prostate cancer aggressiveness</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/prostate_cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/prostate_cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With estimates of 1 600 000 cases and more than 350 000 deaths annually worldwide, prostate cancer is among the most common cancers in men [1]. Diagnosis of prostate cancer is typically done by using ultrasound-guided needle biopsies. An approach that not only involves risks, due to the invasive nature of the method, but also generally underestimates the aggressiveness of the tumor [2]. Standard positron emission tomography (PET) imaging with prostate cancer specific tracers and specifically PSMA-PET have shown to be advantageous for delineating suspicious lesions during biopsy [3, 4].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to use the information provided by these PET and multi-parametric MRI images to directly predict Gleason scores that accurately report the aggressiveness of the prostate cancers without the risks associated with an invasive biopsy. Recent research at our institution has produced promising results predicting Gleason scores from handcrafted radiomic features [5]. This work aims at building on top of this research and to develop an end-to-end deep learning pipeline for predicting tumor aggressiveness directly from different imaging modalities. We have exclusive access to a dataset which includes PSMA-11 PET/MRI scans, segmentation maps and the pathological information of the tumors. Additional public data is available through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pi-cai.grand-challenge.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PI-CAI Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The focus of this work is to build a complete pipeline for analysing multi-modal medical imaging datasets. This includes research on understanding the diverse data available, exploring different approaches for dealing with the limited dataset size (data augmentation, pre-training etc.) and finding a suitable model and evaluation metric for this use case.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. You will establish a comprehensive medical imaging pipeline in PyTorch to extract information from these images. You will be working together with me and under the supervision of Prof. Daniel Rückert. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact medical imaging conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in machine learning and medical imaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python and a common DL framework (PyTorch, Tensorflow).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong interest in teamwork and interdisciplinary research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of highly qualified experts in image processing, computer vision and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] 1. Global Burden of Disease Cancer Collaboration (2017). Global, Regional, and National Cancer Incidence, Mortality, Years of Life Lost, Years Lived With Disability, and Disability-Adjusted Life-years for 32 Cancer Groups, 1990 to 2015: A Systematic Analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study. JAMA Oncol. 2017;3(4):524. &lt;/br&gt;
[2] Cohen et al. (2008). Comparing the Gleason prostate biopsy and Gleason prostatectomy grading system: the Lahey Clinic Medical Center experience and an international meta-analysis. EurUrol. 2008;54(2):371-81. &lt;/br&gt;
[3] Fendler et al. (2017). Joint EANM and SNMMI procedure guideline for prostate cancer imaging: version 1.0. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2017;44(6):1014–24. &lt;/br&gt;
[4] Maurer et al. (2016). Current use of PSMA-PET in prostate cancer management. Nat Rev Urol. 2016;13(4):226–35. &lt;/br&gt;
[5] Solari et al. (2021). The added value of PSMA PET/MR radiomics for prostate cancer staging. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49:527–538.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Adversarial attacks in collaborative machine learning</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Collaborative machine learning has became the new paradigm-of-choice when it comes to training deep learning models in many fields, including medical image analysis. Due to a number of data protection and governance regulations being introduced, direct data sharing for such training is rendered problematic. As a result implementations that rely on local training, such as federated learning (FL) have been widely adopted. However, a number of studies [1,2] have shown that such paradigms are deeply vulnerable to adversarial influence either in the form of privacy violation [3] or utility degradation [4]. Fortunately for the research community, such attacks are often very fragile and require a number of assumptions to hold in practise. The aim of this project is to explore the recent advances in adversarial machine learning in order to investigate how to adapt them to the real-world machine learning contexts in order to encourage the research community and policymakers to employ safe, robust and privacy-preserving systems when working with sensitive personally-identifying information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is deliberately very open-ended, as there is a large number of various attack vectors that could be pursued: attacks on membership, reconstruction of sensitive attributes or training samples, insertion of auxiliary learning tasks etc. Our lab has experience primarily with privacy-oriented attacks on machine learning, but we are otherwise happy to consider students with interest in any other attack formulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with existing collaborative machine learning paradigms, preferably federated learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with attacks on machine learning models (all information can be found in the references).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced knowledge of machine learning and computer vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python and PyTorch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to perform cutting edge research in the field of adversarial and privacy-preserving machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closely working and collaborating with a team of experts in privacy-preserving machine learning, deep learning and medical image analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This project is targeting publication at leading privacy and security conferences/journals (e.g. PETS)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Usynin, Dmitrii, et al. &amp;ldquo;Adversarial interference and its mitigations in privacy-preserving collaborative machine learning.&amp;rdquo; Nature Machine Intelligence 3.9 (2021): 749-758.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Usynin, Dmitrii, et al. &amp;ldquo;Distributed Machine Learning and the Semblance of Trust.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:2112.11040 (2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Shokri, Reza, et al. &amp;ldquo;Membership inference attacks against machine learning models.&amp;rdquo; 2017 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP). IEEE, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] Bagdasaryan, Eugene, et al. &amp;ldquo;How to backdoor federated learning.&amp;rdquo; International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics. PMLR, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Defending collaborative machine learning through interpretability methods</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/attacks_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/attacks_path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Collaborative machine learning has became the new paradigm-of-choice when it comes to training deep learning models in many fields, including medical image analysis. Due to a number of data protection and governance regulations being introduced, direct data sharing for such training is rendered problematic. As a result implementations that rely on local training, such as federated learning (FL) have been widely adopted. However, a number of studies [1,2] have shown that such paradigms are deeply vulnerable to adversarial influence either in the form of privacy violation [3] or utility degradation [4].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to unite the areas of interpretable deep learning and defenses against attacks on collaborative learning. A number of approaches identifying the so-called critical neurons and pathways have previously been proposed to aid the community in interpretation of the predictions made by deep learning models[5,6,7]. We want to determine if these neurons/pathways are also critical for the adversary when it comes to extraction of information or destruction of utility of a jointly trained model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with existing collaborative machine learning paradigms, preferably federated learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with attacks on machine learning models (all information can be found in the references).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced knowledge of machine learning and computer vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python and PyTorch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to perform cutting edge research in the field of adversarial and privacy-preserving machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closely working and collaborating with a team of experts in privacy-preserving machine learning, deep learning and medical image analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This project is targeting publication at leading privacy and security conferences/journals (e.g. PETS)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Usynin, Dmitrii, et al. &amp;ldquo;Adversarial interference and its mitigations in privacy-preserving collaborative machine learning.&amp;rdquo; Nature Machine Intelligence 3.9 (2021): 749-758.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Usynin, Dmitrii, et al. &amp;ldquo;Distributed Machine Learning and the Semblance of Trust.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:2112.11040 (2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Shokri, Reza, et al. &amp;ldquo;Membership inference attacks against machine learning models.&amp;rdquo; 2017 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP). IEEE, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] Bagdasaryan, Eugene, et al. &amp;ldquo;How to backdoor federated learning.&amp;rdquo; International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics. PMLR, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] Khakzar, Ashkan, et al. &amp;ldquo;Neural response interpretation through the lens of critical pathways.&amp;rdquo; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition. 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6] Zhang, Yang, et al. &amp;ldquo;Fine-grained neural network explanation by identifying input features with predictive information.&amp;rdquo; Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 34 (2021): 20040-20051.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[7] Bau, David, et al. &amp;ldquo;Network dissection: Quantifying interpretability of deep visual representations.&amp;rdquo; Proceedings of the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition. 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.Sc. Thesis: Collection of a German Biomedical Text Corpus from Public Sources</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/data_collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/data_collection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent successes in Natural Language Processing (NLP) are based on pre-training language models on large datasets of unlabelled text.
In the medical domain however, such large datasets are hard to acquire. Especially in the German Medical domain, very few public text datasets are available which limits the availability of pre-trained language models and therefore the success of NLP in this domain.
Instead fo relying on clinical texts that are typically hard to acquire due to privacy issues, we will therefore create a large German Medical corpus based on public sources.
These public sources include academic publications and book, dissertations (e.g. from the university library), and online sources like Wikipedia.
Additionally, we will create a smaller paired German-English corpus from bilingual thesauri and ontologies like the Unified Medical Language System (UMLS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-tasks-include&#34;&gt;Your tasks include&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selection of sources for the corpus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic extraction from the sources (e.g. web crawling, text/section extraction from pdf-files, extraction from structured files like csv or xml) and data cleaning (if required)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Definition of the target structure for the corpus and integrating of all selected sources into this structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explorative data analysis, i.e. computing dataset statistics and visualising properties of the dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in web crawling or data collection is preferable but not required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Experience with machine learning is NOT required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Module IN2409: Inverse Problems in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/post/inverse-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 13:45:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/post/inverse-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This module will be held as a &lt;em&gt;joint online course&lt;/em&gt; between Technical University of Munich (TUM) and  Graz University of Technology (TUG). We offer an interactive lecture, theoretical and practical exercises, as well as international networking opportunities to our students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lecture-content&#34;&gt;Lecture Content&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction, Basics and Applications, Definition Inverse Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Eigenvalue Problem, solving Quadratic Inverse Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singular Value Decomposition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inverse Methods Based on Length&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Generalized Inverse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nonlinear Inverse Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regularization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inverse Problems in Imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application: Computed Tomography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application: Magnetic Resonance Imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections to Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;target-group&#34;&gt;Target Group&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Master&amp;rsquo;s students and PhD students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in Mathematics, Biomedical Imaging, Magnetic Resonance Imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students of Informatics, Mathematics, Biomedical Engineering, Physics and related studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Required: Basic knowledge of Mathematics (Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s courses)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;registration&#34;&gt;Registration&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration has to be conducted in TUMonline. Registration is open for students of Informatics, students from other fields can be manually enrolled to the courses. The module IN2409 consists of a lecture class and an exercise class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:k.hammernik@tum.de&#34;&gt;Kerstin Hammernik&lt;/a&gt;, Technical University of Munich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:c.graf@tugraz.at&#34;&gt;Christina Graf&lt;/a&gt;, Graz University of Technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: AI against SARS-CoV-2</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/ai-virus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/ai-virus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Viruses interact with cellular proteins to replicate and spread. We aim to gain functional insights into the mode of action of cellular proteins, enabling us to better understand how different viruses like SARS-CoV-2 cause disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are using genetic ablation of cellular proteins and viruses that express a green fluorescent protein (GFP), allowing us to continuously follow the infection by live-cell fluorescent microscopy in a time-resolved manner.  The resulting, very rich dataset (consisting of ~60.000 images per virus tested), will be used to search for patterns allowing to classify the function of the perturbed gene in relation to the infecting virus.  For instance, the GFP intensity/area, the localization, and spatial proximity of a GFP signal over time contains information on virus replication and spread.  This work aims to establish and apply unbiased machine learning algorithms to understand these functional links between the cell and the viruses and to identify the proteins and perturbations that contribute to virus growth and virus restriction. This algorithm will further be used to study the influence of inflammatory events and treatment with drug libraries.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student who will establish a comprehensive bioinformatics pipeline to extract information from these images. You will be working together with computational scientists at the AI in Medicine Lab and wet-lab scientists (Prof. Andreas Pichlmair group, Virology). Importantly, your results will be functionally tested iteratively and used to further improve the predictive power of your model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong background in deep learning and image analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong interest in working in an interdisciplinary team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of experts in image processing, deep learning, biology and medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Contrastive Pre-Training for Radiology Reports</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/report_pretraining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/report_pretraining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years transformer-based language models have proven quite successful in the field of natural language processing (NLP).
These models require huge amounts of training data and are therefore typically pre-trained on unlabelled datasets using self-supervised objectives
like masked language modelling (MLM) as proposed in BERT [1].
While models like BioBERT [2] are pre-trained on the medical domain, the used pre-training objectives like MLM treat text as independent sentences and do not utilise the structure of medical documents.
In this project we instead make use of the semi-structured nature of radiology reports and apply contrastive methods on the sections of these reports.
Your task is the adaptation of such contrastive methods (e.g. SimCLR [3], BYOL [4], DINO [5], …) to be used effectively on language models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A strong research group with lots of practical experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutting-edge research in Medical NLP with the opportunity to publish your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python and deep learning frameworks like PyTorch, JAX, or Tensorflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong background in deep learning, preferable (but not required) with experience in NLP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with self-supervised methods like SimCLR is preferable but not required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[1] J. Devlin et al. “Bert: Pre-training of deep bidirectional transformers for language understanding.”  arXiv preprint &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.04805&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[arXiv:1810.04805]&lt;/a&gt; (2018).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2] J. Lee et al. “BioBERT: a pre-trained biomedical language representation model for biomedical text mining.” Bioinformatics 4.36 &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics/article/36/4/1234/5566506&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; (2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[3] T. Chen et al. “Big Self-Supervised Models are Strong Semi-Supervised Learners.” NeurIPS &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.10029&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[arXiv:2006.10029]&lt;/a&gt; (2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[4] J. Grill et al. “Bootstrap Your Own Latent A New Approach to Self-Supervised Learning.” NIPS &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.nips.cc/paper/2020/file/f3ada80d5c4ee70142b17b8192b2958e-Paper.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; (2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[5] M. Caron et al. &amp;ldquo;Emerging Properties in Self-Supervised Vision Transformers.&amp;rdquo; ICCV &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2104.14294&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[arXiv:2104.14294]&lt;/a&gt; (2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Unsupervised deep learning for vessel segmentation in optical coherence tomography angiographs</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/old/octa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/old/octa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Optical coherence tomography angiography (OCTA) is an imaging technique that visualizes blood vessels by detecting motion of red blood cells in sequential scans [1]. It has seen initial adoption for the diagnosis and monitoring of clinical conditions that affect the retinal vasculature, such as several different eye diseases or multiple sclerosis [2, 3]. However, its effective clinical use is often impeded by the occurrence of imaging artifacts and lack of tools that can extract the vessel maps from the images. Only few studies have explored the use of deep-learning-based segmentation to delineate vessels in two-dimensional OCTA images [4, 5]. The development of three-dimensional (3D) segmentation algorithms has proven difficult due to a lack of publicly available datasets with ground truth annotations, which are difficult and time-consuming to acquire for the large and complex OCTA images [5].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims at tackling the problem of 3D vessel segmentation in OCTA images using unsupervised and weakly supervised deep learning. The prospective student will adopt existing deep-learning-based segmentation algorithms so that these can be trained using self-supervision and noisy annotations. All developed methods will be evaluated on a large dataset of OCTA images collected at the Klinikum rechts der Isar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for deep learning and biomedical imaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced knowledge of machine learning and computer vision. Ideally, prior work experience using deep learning for image processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python, PyTorch or Tensorflow. Familiarity with C++ is helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of experts in image processing, deep learning, biomedical engineering and medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] De Carlo, T. E., Romano, A., Waheed, N. K., &amp;amp; Duker, J. S. (2015). A review of optical coherence tomography angiography (OCTA). International journal of retina and vitreous, 1(1), 5. &lt;/br&gt;
[2] Chalam, K. V., &amp;amp; Sambhav, K. (2016). Optical coherence tomography angiography in retinal diseases. Journal of ophthalmic &amp;amp; vision research, 11(1), 84. &lt;/br&gt;
[3] Feucht, N., Maier, M., Lepennetier, G., Pettenkofer, M., Wetzlmair, C., Daltrozzo, T., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Knier, B. (2019). Optical coherence tomography angiography indicates associations of the retinal vascular network and disease activity in multiple sclerosis. Multiple Sclerosis Journal, 25(2), 224-234. &lt;/br&gt;
[4] Mou, L., Zhao, Y., Chen, L., Cheng, J., Gu, Z., Hao, H., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Liu, J. (2019, October). CS-Net: channel and spatial attention network for curvilinear structure segmentation. In International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention (pp. 721-730). Springer, Cham. &lt;/br&gt;
[5] Ma, Y., Hao, H., Xie, J., Fu, H., Zhang, J., Yang, J., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Zhao, Y. (2020). ROSE: a retinal OCT-angiography vessel segmentation dataset and new model. IEEE transactions on medical imaging, 40(3), 928-939. &lt;/br&gt;
[6] Schneider, M., Reichold, J., Weber, B., Székely, G., &amp;amp; Hirsch, S. (2012). Tissue metabolism driven arterial tree generation. Medical image analysis, 16(7), 1397-1414. &lt;/br&gt;
[7] Kato, H., Beker, D., Morariu, M., Ando, T., Matsuoka, T., Kehl, W., &amp;amp; Gaidon, A. (2020). Differentiable rendering: A survey. arXiv preprint arXiv:2006.12057.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Prediction of long-term cognitive outcome in Stroke patients using machine learning</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/stroke/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/stroke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning, in particular deep learning, has reformed the research in the field of medical imaging, and the focus of this project will be on its use for the prediction of disease progression/ neurological outcome in stroke patients. Stroke patients have a high risk of developing dementia (incidence around 20%) within a few months after the event, but so far the reasons and mechanisms are poorly understood [1]. Clinical parameters, such as age, smoking habit and previous health conditions have an influence, but are not sufficient to reliably predict the cognitive outcome. Imaging, for example magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), becomes increasingly important.
The objective of this thesis is to develop a learning-based pipeline, and investigate and identify imaging biomarkers from structural and diffusion MRI to predict poststroke dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience and good understanding in machine learning and statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very good programming skills in python (and pytorch).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in medical imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F. A. Wollenweber et al.: The Determinants of Dementia After Stroke (DEDEMAS) Study: protocol and pilot data. International Journal of Stroke 9(3) (2014): 387-392.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Machine Learning for Analysis of Sarcoma</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/old/sarcoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/old/sarcoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early diagnosis of musculoskeletal tumours is crucial for successful therapy and treatment. The sooner a potential malignant growth is detected, the more effective the next steps in therapy and the better a prognosis usually becomes. The rarity of musculoskeletal tumours, potentially inexperienced clinicians with this certain entity, as well as unspecific anamnesis and clinical manifestations may delay the final diagnosis. Whereas currently available imaging modalities yield considerable insights into tumour staging and grading, biopsy remains the gold standard for final diagnosis. Yet, the planning of a successful biopsy yielding sufficient material might require time aside from a high level of experience and may delay the final diagnosis even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complexity in conjunction with multimodal approaches in fully grasping this disease provide a very suitable foundation for modern artificial intelligence algorithms. Not only for diagnostic purposes, but also for treatment planning or prognosis prediction, machine learning and deep learning algorithms are popular techniques in many disciplines at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasks&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various topics in the domain of musculoskeletal tumor analysis are available for a master thesis in computer science and can be discussed during an interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main tasks will involve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of sarcoma with machine/deep learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coping with very limited and unbalanced datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adaption to medicine specific issues with AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presenting and discussing results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to very rare medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highly educated &amp;amp; interdisciplinary environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top level hardware for scientific computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constant feedback from medical and computer science experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced knowledge of deep learning with imaging data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beneficial but not necessary: experience in medicine / oncology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Rechl H, Kirchhoff C, Wörtler K, Lenze U, Töpfer A, von Eisenhart-Rothe R. Diagnostik von malignen Knochen- und Weichteiltumoren [Diagnosis of malignant bone and soft tissue tumors]. Orthopade. 2011 Oct;40(10):931-41; quiz 942-3. German. doi: 10.1007/s00132-011-1821-7. PMID: 21874363&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] He, Y. et al. Deep learning-based classification of primary bone tumors on radiographs: A preliminary study. EBioMedicine 62, 103121 (2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Hussain Z, Gimenez F, Yi D, Rubin D. Differential Data Augmentation Techniques for Medical Imaging Classification Tasks. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2018;2017:979-984. Published 2018 Apr 16.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar on Federated Learning (SoSe2021)</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/federated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/federated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://campus.tum.de/tumonline/WBMODHB.wbShowMHBReadOnly?pKnotenNr=1248712&amp;amp;pOrgNr=14189&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Master Seminar (IN2107, IN4410)&lt;/a&gt; (2 SWS, 5 ECTS) offered for BioMedical Computing (BMC) program at the Chair for Computer Aided Medical Procedures and Augmented Reality, TU Munich&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizers:&lt;/strong&gt; Dr. Shadi Albarqouni, Helmholtz AI and TU Munich, Prof. Nassir Navab, Chair for Computer Aided Medical Procedures, and Prof. Daniel Rueckert, Chair for AI in Medicine, TU Munich&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tutors&lt;/strong&gt;: Cosmin Bercea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: Fridays, 10:00 - 12:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the great success of our on-going seminar on Deep Learning for Medical Applications, we would like to discuss advanced topics that are quite relevant to Federated Learning which becomes an interesting and hot research direction in the community. In simple words, Federated Learning enables training models at the client-side while preserving their privacy, and aggregates the knowledge from the nodes to learn a global model. The interesting part here that the data are kept private and not transmitted to any other nodes. Instead, the characteristics (e.g. parameters) of the global model are shared with the clients, and once the training is done locally, the characteristics are sent back to the global one for aggregation. This learning paradigm has been received quite nicely in the community, in particular, for sensitive domains, e.g. Healthcare. To push this momentum, we proposed, together with our academia and industry partners, a workshop on Federated, Collaborative, and Distributed Learning in the International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer-Aided Intervention (MICCAI) to attract significant contributions attacking the challenges in Medical Imaging and Healthcare. In this seminar, we will be discussing the relevant papers on Federated Learning with an emphasis on the papers tackling the common challenges in Medical Imaging, e.g. data heterogeneity, domain shift, and non-iid distributed data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For full details on the course please follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://albarqouni.github.io/courses/flhsose2021/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The developing Human Connectome Project (dHCP) automated resting-state functional processing framework for newborn infants</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/publication/neuroimage2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 21:26:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/publication/neuroimage2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Distributionally robust neural networks in medical imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/old/robust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/old/robust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep learning has revolutionized the field of medical imaging. However, the performance of a model drops when the distribution of the test data is different from the distribution of the training data. This is especially critical in a medical setting, where the amount of labelled training data is often limited, and in particular for the application in clinical routine, where the distribution of the test data cannot be controlled. Typical problems are here domain shift, bias in the training data and out-of-distribution samples (e.g., pathologies, image artefacts).
In this project, we will explore distributionally robust optimization (DRO) [1,2] for deep learning in medical imaging. Instead of minimizing the average loss of a training set, DRO minimizes the worst-case risk and with this optimizes the performances on ”hard” examples. The student will adapt and develop novel methods using DRO for medical imaging applications (classification, segmentation and/or registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience and good understanding in machine learning and statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very good programming skills in python (and pytorch).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J. Duchi and H. Namkoong: Learning models with uniform performance via distributionally robust optimization. arXiv preprint arXiv:1810.08750 (2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;S. Sagawa et al.: Distributionally Robust Neural Networks, In Proc. ICLR (2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Out-of-distribution detection using contrastive training for medical imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/old/oodd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/old/oodd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep learning has revolutionized the field of medical imaging. However, the performance of a model drops when the distribution of the test data is different from the distribution of the training data. This is especially critical in a medical setting, where the amount of labelled training data is often limited, and in particular for the application in clinical routine, where the distribution of the test data cannot be controlled. The automatic detection of such Out-of-Distribution (OoD) samples at inference is important for the design of reliable models, but also to identify poor quality images and pathologies not seen during training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, contrastive learning has shown to provide state-of-the-art results for OoD in image classification benchmarks [1]. Contrastive learning is an approach to formulate the task of finding similar and dissimilar samples during training. One advantage of the proposed method is that no OoD data is required during training.
The aim of this project is to explore OoD detection in deep learning in general, and in particular the use of contrastive training. The student will develop and implement (novel) methods for image classification, segmentation, and/or registration in a medical application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience and good understanding in machine learning and statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very good programming skills in python (and pytorch).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J. Winkens et al.: Contrastive Training for Improved Out-of-Distribution Detection. arXiv preprint arXiv:2007.05566 (2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Privacy-preserving Deep Learning in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/ppml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/ppml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Privacy-preserving artificial intelligence techniques such as differential privacy, encryption and multi-party computation can reconcile the needs for data utilisation and data protection in the medical domain, as mandated by legal and ethical requirements. Their widespread utilisation requires innovations in the fields of distributed machine learning (federated learning) as well as answering open questions in privacy research and cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are seeking an MSc candidate with a strong background in machine learning, preferrably with previous exposure to medical imaging topics to complete their thesis at our institute. Experience with distributed systems, privacy and security issues or cryptology is desirable.
We are offering an engaging work environment, a large, diverse team, close personal supervision and collaboration with AI, medical and privacy-preserving ML experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can accommodate a wide range of interests from your side! Please get in touch with us to find an appropriate topic. We are also able to supervise guided research projects, smaller in scope than full MSc theses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model-Based and Data-Driven Strategies in Medical Image Computing</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/publication/proc-ieee-2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 12:39:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/publication/proc-ieee-2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure, privacy-preserving and federated machine learning in medical imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/www.nature.com/articles/s42256-020-0186-1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 06:59:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/www.nature.com/articles/s42256-020-0186-1</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Anschrift&lt;/h3&gt;
Technische Universität München &lt;br&gt;
Arcisstraße 21 &lt;br&gt;
80333 München &lt;br&gt;
Umsatzsteueridentifikationsnummer: DE811193231
&lt;h3&gt;Zuständige Aufsichtsbehörde&lt;/h3&gt;
Bayerisches Staatsministerium für Wissenschaft und Kunst
&lt;h3&gt;Inhaltlich verantwortlich&lt;/h3&gt;
Prof. Dr. Daniel Rückert&lt;br&gt;
Technische Universität München / Klinikum Rechts der Isar&lt;br&gt;
Lehrstuhl für Artificial Intelligence in Medicine and Healthcare&lt;br&gt;
TranslaTUM&lt;br&gt;
Einsteinstraße 25&lt;br&gt;
81675 München&lt;br&gt;
E-Mail: daniel(dot)rueckert(at)tum(dot)de&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Haftungshinweis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trotz sorgfältiger inhaltlicher Kontrolle übernehmen wir keine Haftung für die Inhalte externer Links. Für den Inhalt der verlinkten Seiten sind ausschließlich deren Betreiber verantwortlich. Namentlich gekennzeichnete Beiträge in den Diskussionsbereichen geben die Meinung des Autors wieder. Für die Inhalte der Beiträge sind ausschließlich die Autoren zuständig.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A population-based phenome-wide association study of cardiac and aortic structure and function</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/publication/nat-med-2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:33:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/publication/nat-med-2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic and functional insights into the fractal structure of the heart</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/publication/nat-2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:33:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/publication/nat-2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
