<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Florian A. Hölzl | AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/florian-a.-holzl/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/author/florian-a.-holzl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Florian A. Hölzl</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Technical University of Munich 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aim-lab.io/author/florian-a.-holzl/avatar_hu85e27d71119a00c103faf77f28da5c05_1406585_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Florian A. Hölzl</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/florian-a.-holzl/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis/Guided Research/IDP: Efficient Training under Differential Privacy</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/florianhoelzl/efficient_training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/florianhoelzl/efficient_training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Differential privacy (DP) is the gold standard of privacy-preserving deep learning and has seen increasing interest in the last few years, especially in the medical domain, where the protection of sensitive data is of highest interest [1]. Privacy in deep learning, however, still comes at a high privacy-utility trade-off that restricts the practical usability of models trained under DP. We, as researchers, try to solve this issue by looking into learning theory and by developing novel approaches that allow DP networks to challenge non-private approaches in clinical application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two properties that affect all differentially private networks are model size and the chosen privacy parameters during training. In this work, we plan to analyze these two areas and introduce changes to the training regime, that improve not only the performance of the models but also reduce their computational overhead. The goal is to 1) build on top of research done on learning sparse neural networks and correspondingly adapt the model parameters during training [2]. And 2), we look at the amount of total noise added during training with DP and evaluate, how to adapt the corresponding privacy parameters without any knowledge about the model or dataset [3]. If successful, this research can be applied to any differential private model in a plug-and-play fashion during training to further reduce the privacy-utility trade-off.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. You will establish a comprehensive pipeline in PyTorch or JAX to evaluate the model sparsity and changing privacy-parameters on different benchmark datasets for models trained under DP. You will be working at the institute for AI in Medicine, at the Privacy-Preserving and Trustworthy Machine Learning Group. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact deep learning conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in deep learning and learning theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python and a common DL framework (PyTorch, Tensorflow, JAX).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent working style with strong interest in teamwork and methodic research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting state-of-the-art research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to the necessary computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of highly qualified experts in image processing, computer vision and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Abadi et al. (2016). Deep Learning with Differential Privacy. ACM SIGSAC 2016. &lt;/br&gt;
[2] Louizos et al. (2018). Learning sparse neural networks through L0 regularization. ICLR 2018. &lt;/br&gt;
[3] Sander et al. (2022). TAN without a burn: Scaling Laws of DP-SGD. ArXiv, abs/2210.03403.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Scaling Laws of Equivariant Convolutions</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/florianhoelzl/scaling_laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/florianhoelzl/scaling_laws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Equivariant convolutions are a novel approach that incorporate additional geometric properties of the input domain during the convolution process (i.e. symmetry properties such as rotations and reflections) [1]. This additional inductive bias allows the model to learn more robust and general features from less data, rendering them highly promising for application in the medical domain. So far, however, nobody has investigated how their beneficial characteristics impact the design and scaling of deep learning model architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have developed a framework for initial investigation of equivariant convolutions and now want to evaluate how their performance can be further increased with larger model sizes and under different training regimes. This work plans to build onto previous highly impactful research on model design, such as the establishment of the EfficientNet architecture and the Chinchilla language model, to create a sound basis for the further consolidation of equivariant convolutions in the broader research landscape [2, 3]. The focus will be to thoroughly analyze and expand a framework for equivariant models already developed at our lab. This includes getting familiar with model architectures in general, the properties of equivariant convolutions and the intersection of the two. Our goal is to develop a methodological framework for equivariant model architectures that can be easily adapted to the properties of the used dataset and are able to beat state-of-the-art non-equivariant alternatives in standard and privacy-preserving deep learning settings [4].
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. You will establish a comprehensive pipeline in PyTorch or JAX to evaluate the properties of equivariant models on different benchmark datasets. You will be working at the institute for AI in Medicine, at the Privacy-Preserving and Trustworthy Machine Learning Group. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact deep learning conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in deep learning and learning theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python and a common DL framework (PyTorch, Tensorflow, JAX).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent working style with strong interest in teamwork and methodic research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting state-of-the-art research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to the necessary computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of highly qualified experts in image processing, computer vision and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Cohen and Welling (2016). Group Equivariant Convolutions. ICML 2016. &lt;/br&gt;
[2] Tan and Le (2019). EfficientNet: Rethinking Model Scaling for Convolutional Neural Networks. ICML 2019. &lt;/br&gt;
[3] Hoffmann et al. (2022). Training Compute-Optimal Large Language Models. ArXiv, abs/2203.15556. &lt;/br&gt;
[4] Abadi et al. (2016). Deep Learning with Differential Privacy. ACM SIGSAC 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Non-invasive and accurate prediction of prostate cancer aggressiveness</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/florianhoelzl/prostate_cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/florianhoelzl/prostate_cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With estimates of 1 600 000 cases and more than 350 000 deaths annually worldwide, prostate cancer is among the most common cancers in men [1]. Diagnosis of prostate cancer is typically done by using ultrasound-guided needle biopsies. An approach that not only involves risks, due to the invasive nature of the method, but also generally underestimates the aggressiveness of the tumor [2]. Standard positron emission tomography (PET) imaging with prostate cancer specific tracers and specifically PSMA-PET have shown to be advantageous for delineating suspicious lesions during biopsy [3, 4].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to use the information provided by these PET and multi-parametric MRI images to directly predict Gleason scores that accurately report the aggressiveness of the prostate cancers without the risks associated with an invasive biopsy. Recent research at our institution has produced promising results predicting Gleason scores from handcrafted radiomic features [5]. This work aims at building on top of this research and to develop an end-to-end deep learning pipeline for predicting tumor aggressiveness directly from different imaging modalities. We have exclusive access to a dataset which includes PSMA-11 PET/MRI scans, segmentation maps and the pathological information of the tumors. Additional public data is available through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pi-cai.grand-challenge.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PI-CAI Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The focus of this work is to build a complete pipeline for analysing multi-modal medical imaging datasets. This includes research on understanding the diverse data available, exploring different approaches for dealing with the limited dataset size (data augmentation, pre-training etc.) and finding a suitable model and evaluation metric for this use case.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. You will establish a comprehensive medical imaging pipeline in PyTorch to extract information from these images. You will be working together with me and under the supervision of Prof. Daniel Rückert. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact medical imaging conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in machine learning and medical imaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in Python and a common DL framework (PyTorch, Tensorflow).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong interest in teamwork and interdisciplinary research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of highly qualified experts in image processing, computer vision and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] 1. Global Burden of Disease Cancer Collaboration (2017). Global, Regional, and National Cancer Incidence, Mortality, Years of Life Lost, Years Lived With Disability, and Disability-Adjusted Life-years for 32 Cancer Groups, 1990 to 2015: A Systematic Analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study. JAMA Oncol. 2017;3(4):524. &lt;/br&gt;
[2] Cohen et al. (2008). Comparing the Gleason prostate biopsy and Gleason prostatectomy grading system: the Lahey Clinic Medical Center experience and an international meta-analysis. EurUrol. 2008;54(2):371-81. &lt;/br&gt;
[3] Fendler et al. (2017). Joint EANM and SNMMI procedure guideline for prostate cancer imaging: version 1.0. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2017;44(6):1014–24. &lt;/br&gt;
[4] Maurer et al. (2016). Current use of PSMA-PET in prostate cancer management. Nat Rev Urol. 2016;13(4):226–35. &lt;/br&gt;
[5] Solari et al. (2021). The added value of PSMA PET/MR radiomics for prostate cancer staging. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49:527–538.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
