<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Johannes C. Paetzold | AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/johannes-c.-paetzold/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/author/johannes-c.-paetzold/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Johannes C. Paetzold</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Technical University of Munich 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aim-lab.io/images/icon_hu90763c276d9f69c3ad22e431a6bb6670_11797_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Johannes C. Paetzold</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/johannes-c.-paetzold/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDP/Guided Research/Thesis: Improving topological correctness with total variation</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/aberger/tv/index_tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/aberger/tv/index_tv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Topological correctness, i.e., the preservation of structural integrity and specific characteristics of shape, is a fundamental requirement for medical imaging tasks, such as neuron or vessel segmentation. However, most networks are trained using pixel-wise loss functions such as Dice, neglecting topological accuracy. Recently, significant methodological advancements have applied well-founded concepts from algebraic topology to topologically accurate binary segmentation [1,2,3,4]. However, these solutions are often computational expensive and do not match the runtime speed of pixel-wise loss functions, such as Dice. Total variation is a promising method to efficiently improve topological accuracy with interesting theoretical ties to persistent homology [5].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on applying total variation as a novel method for efficient topology aware image segmentation. Note that we also offer other projects in the field of topology-preserving image segmentation. For more information, see our profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the current state-of-the-art techniques for topologically accurate image segmentation and total variation in image segmentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formulation of a total variation loss for image segmentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison to existing baseline methods in terms of pixel-wise, overlap-based, and topological accuracy with a focus on computational efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparation and submission of a peer-reviewed publication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated student in Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics or Engineering. Your goal is to explore the potential of total variation as an efficient method for topology-aware image segmentation. You will be working with Alex and Laurin, two PhD candidates at TU Munich, and Johannes, an appointed assistant professor at Cornell University. Prof. Daniel Rueckert will be the project supervisor. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work with you in a follow-up study at a high-impact machine learning conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong academic record (e.g. high GPA in current and previous studies).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in C++, Python or C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for teamwork and interdisciplinary research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities for bringing your own ideas into the field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on experience with state-of-the-art machine learning architectures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a collaborative (TUM and Cornell) team of highly qualified experts in machine learning, computer vision, and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to apply:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:a.berger@tum.de&#34;&gt;a.berger@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:laurin.lux@tum.de&#34;&gt;laurin.lux@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jpaetzold@med.cornell.edu&#34;&gt;jpaetzold@med.cornell.edu&lt;/a&gt;, with a short CV and your grade report. We promise to get back to you within days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Lux, L., Berger, A. H., Weers, A., Stucki, N., Rueckert, D., Bauer, U., &amp;amp; Paetzold, J. C. (2024). Topograph: An efficient Graph-Based Framework for Strictly Topology Preserving Image Segmentation. arXiv preprint arXiv:2411.03228.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Berger, A. H., Lux, L., Stucki N, Bürgin, V., Shit S., Banaszak A., Rueckert D., Bauer U., Paetzold J. C. (2024) Topologically faithful multi-class segmentation in medical images. International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Stucki, N., Paetzold, J. C., Shit, S., Menze, B., &amp;amp; Bauer, U. (2023, July). Topologically faithful image segmentation via induced matching of persistence barcodes. In International Conference on Machine Learning (pp. 32698-32727). PMLR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] Stucki, N., Bürgin, V., Paetzold, J. C., &amp;amp; Bauer, U. (2024). Efficient Betti Matching Enables Topology-Aware 3D Segmentation via Persistent Homology. arXiv preprint arXiv:2407.04683.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] Bauer, U., Schoenlieb, CB., Wardetzky, M. (2010). Total variation meets topological persistence: A first encounter. AIP Conference Proceedings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDP/Guided Research/Thesis: Multiclass Interactions for topologically accurate image segmentation</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/aberger/tvr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/aberger/tvr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Topological correctness, i.e., the preservation of structural integrity and specific characteristics of shape, is a fundamental requirement for medical imaging tasks, such as neuron or vessel segmentation. However, most networks are trained using pixel-wise loss functions such as Dice, neglecting topological accuracy. Recently, significant methodological advancements have applied well-founded concepts from algebraic topology to topologically-accurate binary segmentation [1,2,3,4]. However, these approaches have been underexplored in multi-class segmentation scenarios, where topological errors are common. Especially the topological interactions between multiple classes are often disregarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on developing novel image segmentation methods that maintain topological-accuracy in complex multiclass scenarios. Your approach will build on recent advances in topological loss functions for training segmentation networks [1,3,4] and will be applied to highly relevant medical tasks, such as cerebrovascular segmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that we also offer other projects in the field of topology-preserving image segmentation. For more information, see our profiles.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;topcow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image topcow&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review on the current state-of-the-art techniques for topologically-accurate image segmentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of relevant medical multiclass segmentation tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extension of a topology-preserving image segmentation method to account for complex multiclass interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison to existing baseline methods in terms of pixel-wise, overlap-based, and topological accuracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparation and submission of a peer-reviewed publication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. Your goal is to develop a topologically-accurate image segmentation method with special regard to multiclass interactions and compare them to alternative approaches. You will be working together with Alex and Laurin, two research scientist at TU Munich, as well as Johannes, an appointed assistant professor at Cornell University. Supervision will be provided by Prof. Daniel Rueckert. Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact machine learning conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong academic record (e.g. high GPA in current and previous studies).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in C++, Python or C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for teamwork and interdisciplinary research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on experience with state-of-the-art machine learning architectures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a collaborative (TUM and Cornell) team of highly qualified experts in machine learning, computer vision, and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to apply:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:a.berger@tum.de&#34;&gt;a.berger@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:laurin.lux@tum.de&#34;&gt;laurin.lux@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jpaetzold@med.cornell.edu&#34;&gt;jpaetzold@med.cornell.edu&lt;/a&gt;, with a short CV and your grade report. We promise to get back to you within days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Lux, L., Berger, A. H., Weers, A., Stucki, N., Rueckert, D., Bauer, U., &amp;amp; Paetzold, J. C. (2024). Topograph: An efficient Graph-Based Framework for Strictly Topology Preserving Image Segmentation. arXiv preprint arXiv:2411.03228.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Berger, A. H., Lux, L., Stucki N, Bürgin, V., Shit S., Banaszak A., Rueckert D., Bauer U., Paetzold J. C. (2024) Topologically faithful multi-class segmentation in medical images. International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Stucki, N., Paetzold, J. C., Shit, S., Menze, B., &amp;amp; Bauer, U. (2023, July). Topologically faithful image segmentation via induced matching of persistence barcodes. In International Conference on Machine Learning (pp. 32698-32727). PMLR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] Stucki, N., Bürgin, V., Paetzold, J. C., &amp;amp; Bauer, U. (2024). Efficient Betti Matching Enables Topology-Aware 3D Segmentation via Persistent Homology. arXiv preprint arXiv:2407.04683.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] Yang K., Musio F., Ma Y. et al. (2023). Benchmarking the CoW with the TopCoW Challenge: Topology-Aware Anatomical Segmentation of the Circle of Willis for CTA and MRA. arXiv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Self-Supervised Pretraining for Topologically Accurate Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/aberger/top/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/aberger/top/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep-learning models achieve high performance on various biomedical prediction tasks but often rely on extensive annotated datasets. Especially in biomedicine, such datasets are frequently unavailable due to the difficulty and cost of annotation. Self-supervised pre-training methods, such as the masked autoencoder (MAE) [1], have emerged as a promising way to leverage unlabeled data, reducing the need for large annotated datasets. However, these methods often struggle to preserve fine-grained structures, such as alveoli or pulmonary vessels in lung CT scans, which are critical for downstream applications such as disease classification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis focuses on developing novel pre-training strategies to preserve these fine-grained structures in medical images. Specifically, we aim to incorporate methods from digital topology to capture and maintain topological information during image reconstruction. Our approach builds on recent advances in topological loss functions for training segmentation networks [2,3,4].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that we also offer other projects in the field of topology-preserving image segmentation. For more information, see our profiles.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;betti_matching.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image image-to-graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated Master’s student in Computer Science, Physics, Engineering or Mathematics. Your goal is to explore how existing topological loss functions can be used for pre-training and compare them to alternative approaches. You will be working together with Alex and Laurin, two research scientist at TU Munich, as well as Johannes, an appointed assistant professor at Cornell University. Supervision will be provided by Prof. Daniel Rueckert.  Importantly, we aim to publish the results of this work, with you, in a follow up study at a high-impact machine learning conference or in an academic journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong motivation and interest in machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced programming skills in C++, Python or C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for teamwork and interdisciplinary research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exciting research project with many possibilities to bring in your own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision and access to state-of-the-art computer hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The chance to work in a team of highly qualified experts in machine learning, computer vision, and deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to apply:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:a.berger@tum.de&#34;&gt;a.berger@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:laurin.lux@tum.de&#34;&gt;laurin.lux@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jpaetzold@med.cornell.edu&#34;&gt;jpaetzold@med.cornell.edu&lt;/a&gt;, with a short CV and your grade report. We promise to get back to you within days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.melbourneradiology.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/CT-CHEST-0002-1024x1012.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chest CT scan&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] He, K., Chen, X., Xie, S., Li, Y., Dollár, P., &amp;amp; Girshick, R. (2022). Masked autoencoders are scalable vision learners. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF conference on computer vision and pattern recognition (pp. 16000-16009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Lux, L., Berger, A. H., Weers, A., Stucki, N., Rueckert, D., Bauer, U., &amp;amp; Paetzold, J. C. (2024). Topograph: An efficient Graph-Based Framework for Strictly Topology Preserving Image Segmentation. arXiv preprint arXiv:2411.03228.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Stucki, N., Paetzold, J. C., Shit, S., Menze, B., &amp;amp; Bauer, U. (2023, July). Topologically faithful image segmentation via induced matching of persistence barcodes. In International Conference on Machine Learning (pp. 32698-32727). PMLR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] Stucki, N., Bürgin, V., Paetzold, J. C., &amp;amp; Bauer, U. (2024). Efficient Betti Matching Enables Topology-Aware 3D Segmentation via Persistent Homology. arXiv preprint arXiv:2407.04683.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
