<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Current Vacancies on AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Current Vacancies on AI in Medicine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Technical University of Munich {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/theses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Unsupervised deep learning for vessel segmentation in optical coherence tomography angiographs</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/octa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/octa/</guid>
      <description>Optical coherence tomography angiography (OCTA) is an imaging technique that visualizes blood vessels by detecting motion of red blood cells in sequential scans [1]. It has seen initial adoption for the diagnosis and monitoring of clinical conditions that affect the retinal vasculature, such as several different eye diseases or multiple sclerosis [2, 3].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Prediction of long-term cognitive outcome in Stroke patients using machine learning</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/stroke/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/stroke/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning, in particular deep learning, has reformed the research in the field of medical imaging, and the focus of this project will be on its use for the prediction of disease progression/ neurological outcome in stroke patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Machine Learning for Analysis of Sarcoma</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/sarcoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/sarcoma/</guid>
      <description>Description Early diagnosis of musculoskeletal tumours is crucial for successful therapy and treatment. The sooner a potential malignant growth is detected, the more effective the next steps in therapy and the better a prognosis usually becomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Transformer-based Optical Flow Estimation in General Computer Vision</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/transformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/transformer/</guid>
      <description>Description Deep learning has reached a new era in 2021, with Transformer-based networks making a name for themselves in Computer vision tasks, topping the Leaderboard in Recognition, Detection and Segmentation [1-3].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Deep Natural Language Processing for Radiology Reports</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/nlp/</guid>
      <description>In recent years deep learning has proven quite successful in the field of natural language processing (NLP). However, many of today’s NLP models require very large datasets for training, thus self-supervised pre-training (like BERT [1]) on large unlabeled datasets has become quite important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar on Federated Learning (SoSe2021)</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/federated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/federated/</guid>
      <description>Master Seminar (IN2107, IN4410) (2 SWS, 5 ECTS) offered for BioMedical Computing (BMC) program at the Chair for Computer Aided Medical Procedures and Augmented Reality, TU Munich
Organizers: Dr. Shadi Albarqouni, Helmholtz AI and TU Munich, Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Machine Learning in Fetal MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/fetal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/fetal/</guid>
      <description>Fetal Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) has become increasingly important to assess the development of the fetal brain. However, the acquisition is challenging due to the uncontrollable fetal motion. This requires both improved MR acquisition and reconstruction procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Motion-Compensated MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/motionmri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/motionmri/</guid>
      <description>Long acquisition times in Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) bear the risk of patient motion, which substantially degrades the image quality. Further sources of image degradation are physiological motion, such as periodic respiratory and cardiac motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Physics-Driven Self-Supervised Learning in MRI Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/physicsmri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/physicsmri/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning has evolved tremendously to accelerate the inherently low acquisition process of Magnetic Resonance (MR) images. However, it is challenging to obtain ground truth data for learning MRI reconstruction. The objective of this MSc thesis is to explore self-supervised learning for MRI reconstruction, where only the measurement (k-space) data and knowledge about the acquisition physics are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Distributionally robust neural networks in medical imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/robust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/robust/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning has revolutionized the field of medical imaging. However, the performance of a model drops when the distribution of the test data is different from the distribution of the training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Out-of-distribution detection using contrastive training for medical imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/oodd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/oodd/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning has revolutionized the field of medical imaging. However, the performance of a model drops when the distribution of the test data is different from the distribution of the training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Privacy-preserving Deep Learning in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/ppml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/ppml/</guid>
      <description>Privacy-preserving artificial intelligence techniques such as differential privacy, encryption and multi-party computation can reconcile the needs for data utilisation and data protection in the medical domain, as mandated by legal and ethical requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
