<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philip Müller on AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/philip-muller/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philip Müller on AI in Medicine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Technical University of Munich {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/author/philip-muller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Contrastive Pre-Training for Radiology Reports</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/report_pretraining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/report_pretraining/</guid>
      <description>In recent years transformer-based language models have proven quite successful in the field of natural language processing (NLP). These models require huge amounts of training data and are therefore typically pre-trained on unlabelled datasets using self-supervised objectives like masked language modelling (MLM) as proposed in BERT [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Region-guided Chest X-Ray Report Generation</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/report_generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/report_generation/</guid>
      <description>In clinical practice, medical experts like radiologists routinely write radiology reports for chest X-rays. Report generation models [1, 2, 3] try to generate such reports automatically given only the chest X-ray images without the need for human intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Course: Applied Deep Learning in Medicine</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</guid>
      <description>In this course students are given the chance to apply their abilities and knowledge in deep learning to real-world medical data. Students will be assigned a medical dataset and in close consultation with medical doctors create a project plan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
