<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexander Ziller | AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/alexander-ziller/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/author/alexander-ziller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Alexander Ziller</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Technical University of Munich 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aim-lab.io/author/alexander-ziller/avatar_hu88e80638f93b3174cfb75c89a83e2b3e_80953_270x270_fill_q90_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Alexander Ziller</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/alexander-ziller/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Project/Guided Research/etc: Separating the influence of noising and clipping in differentially private training.</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/clipvsnoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/clipvsnoise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Privacy-Preserving Machine Learning enables the training of neural networks, while bounding the information about data subjects [1,2]. Hence, especially in sensitive contexts where plausible deniability is crucial it is an important mean to give mathematical guarantees about worst case guarantees. However, due to these constraints in most cases it introduces a drop in utility compared to non-private training. This noise can be explained from two factors compared to normal training: 1) gradients are clipped to a maximum norm and 2) noise is added. In this project we want to evaluate the effect of both seperately on different architectures and settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced knowledge of machine learning and computer vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python and at least one deep learning frame work (optimally PyTorch or Jax)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior knowledge on PPML or medical imaging is helpful but no requirement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with several top-tier publications in privacy-preserving machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working in an interdisciplinary team of experts in PPML, image processing, deep learning, biomedical engineering and medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enough freedom to pursue your own project while providing the guidance you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thesis is strongly aimed to be published in a peer-reviewed venue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-020-0186-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[1] Secure, privacy-preserving and federated machine learning in medical imaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-021-00337-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[2] End-to-end privacy preserving deep learning on multi-institutional medical imaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Systematic Evaluation of Segmentation Architectures in Private Medical Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/privatesegmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/privatesegmentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Privacy-Preserving Machine Learning enables the training of neural networks, while bounding the information about data subjects [1,2]. Hence, especially in sensitive contexts where plausible deniability is crucial it is an important mean to give mathematical guarantees about worst case guarantees. However, due to these constraints in most cases it introduces a drop in utility compared to non-private training. In recent publications it was shown that the margin between private and non-private training is among other factors dependent on the model architecture [3,4,5]. It is apparent that the rules, which architectures perform best, which have extensively been researched for standard training are different in these settings. First studies in classification settings showed that wider models appear to be advantageous [4,5]. In this thesis we want to systematically evaluate existing segmentation architectures under privacy constraints in medical and non-medical benchmark datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for deep learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced knowledge of machine learning and computer vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python and at least one deep learning frame work (optimally PyTorch or Jax)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior knowledge on PPML or medical imaging is helpful but no requirement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with several top-tier publications in privacy-preserving machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working in an interdisciplinary team of experts in PPML, image processing, deep learning, biomedical engineering and medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enough freedom to pursue your own project while providing the guidance you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thesis is strongly aimed to be published in a peer-reviewed venue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-020-0186-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[1] Secure, privacy-preserving and federated machine learning in medical imaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42256-021-00337-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[2] End-to-end privacy preserving deep learning on multi-institutional medical imaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2203.00324.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[3] Differentially private training of residual networks with scale normalisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2204.13650.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[4] Unlocking high-accuracy differentially private image classification through scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2205.04095.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[5] SmoothNets: Optimizing CNN architecture design for differentially private deep learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Course: Applied Deep Learning in Medicine</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this course students are given the chance to apply their abilities and knowledge in deep learning to real-world medical data. Students will be assigned a medical dataset and in close consultation with medical doctors create a project plan. Deep Learning methods will be applied to solve tasks to achieve the goal that is agreed upon. Datasets will be explored and analysed in several directions and different approaches will be evaluated and compared.
In short this course offers students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply Deep Learning in the real world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on medical data and potentially help diagnose and analyse health related problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision by PhD students with specialization in AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaboration with medical experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on the intersection between medicine and computer science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed at least one or several machine learning or deep learning courses (e.g. Intro to Deep Learning, Advanced Deep Learning, Machine Learning etc) with good grades. Knowledge about augmentation, optimizer, common model architectures, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good coding skills in python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding experience in one or more deep learning frameworks (Tensorflow, PyTorch, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for the application in the medical field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to tackle applied deep learning projects in a structured manner with a good overview of possibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gained insight into the problems of medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final outcome as a useful insight or tool for medical professionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible outcome will be published in a peer-reviewed venue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will work in teams of three&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group will be assigned one medical dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Bi)weekly meetings with progress reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-meeting&#34;&gt;Preliminary meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A preliminary meeting will take place on 31st of January, 2023 at 11:30 on zoom with the following details:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519&#34;&gt;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/69075883519&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting ID: 690 7588 3519&lt;br&gt;
Passcode: 850155&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeetingSoSe23.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides - SoSe 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeetingWS22.pdf&#34;&gt;(Outdated) Slides - WS 2022/23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;PracticalPreMeeting.pdf&#34;&gt;(Outdated) Slides - SoSe 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
