<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philip Mueller | AI in Medicine</title>
    <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/philip-mueller/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://aim-lab.io/author/philip-mueller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Philip Mueller</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Technical University of Munich 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://aim-lab.io/author/philip-mueller/avatar_huebfb1a8f9b03371737ed0e0993aaacc0_14018_270x270_fill_q90_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Philip Mueller</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/author/philip-mueller/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Course: Applied Deep Learning in Medicine</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/practical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this course students are given the chance to apply their abilities and knowledge in deep learning to real-world medical data. Students will be assigned a medical dataset and in close consultation with medical doctors create a project plan. Deep Learning methods will be applied to solve tasks to achieve the goal that is agreed upon. Datasets will be explored and analysed in several directions and different approaches will be evaluated and compared.
In short this course offers students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply Deep Learning in the real world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on medical data and potentially help diagnose and analyse health related problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close supervision of PhD students with specialization in AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaboration with medical experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on the intersection between medicine and computer science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed at least one or several machine learning or deep learning courses (e.g. Intro to Deep Learning, Advanced Deep Learning, Machine Learning etc) with good grades. Knowledge about augmentation, optimizer, common model architectures, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good coding skills in python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding experience in one or more deep learning frameworks (Tensorflow, PyTorch, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enthusiasm for the application in the medical field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to tackle applied deep learning projects in a structured manner with a good overview of possibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gained insight into the problems of medical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final outcome as a useful insight or tool for medical professionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible outcome will be published in a peer-reviewed venue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will work in teams of three&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group will be assigned one medical dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Bi)weekly meetings with progress reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-meeting&#34;&gt;Preliminary meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on this practical we recommend participation in our preliminary meeting taking place &lt;b&gt;2nd of February 2022 at 15:00&lt;/b&gt; on zoom: &lt;/br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/67021473624&#34;&gt;https://tum-conf.zoom.us/j/67021473624&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/br&gt;
Meeting-ID: 670 2147 3624 &lt;/br&gt;
Code: 515230 &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis: Deep Natural Language Processing for Radiology Reports</title>
      <link>https://aim-lab.io/theses/nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aim-lab.io/theses/nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years deep learning has proven quite successful in the field of natural language processing (NLP). However, many of today’s NLP models require very large datasets for training, thus self-supervised pre-training (like BERT [1]) on large unlabeled datasets has become quite important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to apply deep NLP models (like transformers) to radiology reports and do predictions on them. While there is a large variety of pre-trained models available which we could utilize for this task (like [2,3]), these models suffer from a language domain-shift when directly applied to German radiology reports as available models are typically not pre-trained on German medical language.
Thus, our goal is to pre-train a NLP model for the domain of German radiology reports such that the resulting model can be easily fine-tuned for prediction tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We offer flexibility regarding the objectives of this MSc thesis.
Possible tasks may include but are not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain adaptation of pre-trained models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adaption or development of a pre-training strategy for radiology reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of a model architecture for radiology reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of a data augmentation strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilization of additional data sources for pre-training (e.g. Wikipedia or books)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can define the topic of your thesis, such that it matches your interests as good as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong background in deep learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proficient in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with ML frameworks, preferable PyTorch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior experience or knowledge (e.g. lectures) in NLP is beneficial but not required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J. Devlin et al. &amp;ldquo;Bert: Pre-training of deep bidirectional transformers for language understanding.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.04805&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:1810.04805&lt;/a&gt; (2018).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E. Alsentzer et al. “Publicly Available Clinical BERT Embeddings.” arXiv preprint &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1904.03323&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:1904.03323&lt;/a&gt; (2019)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B. Chan et al. “German’s Next Language Model.” arXiv preprint &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2010.10906&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;arXiv:2010.10906&lt;/a&gt; (2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
